<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PJ the Pooh</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.pjthepooh.com/</id><updated>2016-09-17T20:20:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Fall Off the Bike</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/fall-off-the-bike.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T20:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T20:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>PJ</name></author><id>tag:www.pjthepooh.com,2016-09-17:fall-off-the-bike.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is a bad day. I fell off my bike (bicycle, not motorcycle), and it was my first time falling off. As I did not have any protection, except my helmet of course, and it was in a pretty damn fast speed, so my legs and knees were bruised. Most sadly, my bike crashed on the ground and the handler was deformed. Yup, I bought a new bike a month ago and was about to ride it to work on a daily basis. This morning I was trying to get familiar with the route from home to the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Market St. There was a bus stoping in front of me blocking half of the road. I wanted to accelerate and pass it on the left (yes right? You know you won't stop if you are on a two-wheeled machine). How the hell I could not know there are muni tracks on the middle of Market St (yes right? I must have been living in the city for too long to notice it). I should have noticed it, or I should have never passed buses like that, at least not on Market St. When I saw that track, it was already too late. I fell off at about 10 feet away from the bus's front wheel. Fortunately, the bus had not moved yet. It was pretty dangerous when I look back it now. For those who know me enough, they know I often watch video clips like "top 100 car crashes", "Fetal car accidents" or something like that on Youtube, which is kind of weird. I don't know why I like it but I know it reminds me that I need to be always cautious on the road because there are crazy drivers anywhere. They are super dangerous!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loving biking, either bicycle or motorcycle. I'm kind of mad at myself now as not ever having my own motorcycle even although I had a M1 license 6 years ago. I never got any supports when I said "I'm gonna to buy a bike." I understand it not safe and it seems immature in some sense, but should I just be immature at that age? I would not regret even if I fell off from my own bike if I had one, but I kind of regret I have never had one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gotta fix my bike soon, meh...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--![images]({attach}/images/bike_day.JPG)--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bike_day" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/bike_day.JPG" width="353" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="life"></category><category term="biking"></category><category term="bicycling"></category></entry><entry><title>Welcome to My New Blog</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/welcome-to-my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-12T20:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-12T20:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>PJ</name></author><id>tag:www.pjthepooh.com,2016-09-12:welcome-to-my-new-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2 id="what-is-pj-the-pooh"&gt;What is PJ the Pooh?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my nickname created by my girlfriend. This is just my personal page to record my life and share my passion. It is not a pure tech blog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-old-habit"&gt;My old habit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time flies. Last time I blogged was when I was in middle school, which is about a decade ago, when Weibo, Facebook and Twitter did not even exist. I was blogging pretty consistently because it helped calm me down as I was in my teenage rebellion period. Of course, the content was mostly about my little things in life and nothing worthy to read if you didn't know me. More importantly, it reminded me of my old stories reading it years later. All the images and feelings would emerge whenever I read it again. My life has changed since my family and I moved to U.S, and then I stopped this habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-would-i-blog-again"&gt;Why would I blog again?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not? Besides the main reason of simply wanting a space for myself, I have the following reasons why I want to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My own space&lt;/strong&gt; - I have full control of this space, from the server to my words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stays in touch&lt;/strong&gt; -  Mainly to stay in touch with family and friends who I can't see very often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gain knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; - Updating blog regularly is a perfect way to stay tuned with the events in my fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; - It may help others who search for similar topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Store my stuff&lt;/strong&gt; - It would be convenient to find my own stuff in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To practice my writing&lt;/strong&gt; - I am a terrible writer so here I come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To connect with like-minded people&lt;/strong&gt; - Hopefully!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, welcome and please keep in touch!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="life"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>