<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PJ the Pooh</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.pjthepooh.com/</id><updated>2016-09-17T20:20:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Fall Off the Bike</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/fall-off-the-bike.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T20:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T20:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>PJ</name></author><id>tag:www.pjthepooh.com,2016-09-17:fall-off-the-bike.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is a bad day. I fell off my bike (bicycle, not motorcycle), and it was my first time falling off. As I did not have any protection, except my helmet of course, and it was in a pretty damn fast speed, so my legs and knees were bruised. Most sadly, my bike crashed on the ground and the handler was deformed. Yup, I bought a new bike a month ago and was about to ride it to work on a daily basis. This morning I was trying to get familiar with the route from home to the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Market St. There was a bus stoping in front of me blocking half of the road. I wanted to accelerate and pass it on the left (yes right? You know you won't stop if you are on a two-wheeled machine). How the hell I could not know there are muni tracks on the middle of Market St (yes right? I must have been living in the city for too long to notice it). I should have noticed it, or I should have never passed buses like that, at least not on Market St. When I saw that track, it was already too late. I fell off at about 10 feet away from the bus's front wheel. Fortunately, the bus had not moved yet. It was pretty dangerous when I look back it now. For those who know me enough, they know I often watch video clips like "top 100 car crashes", "Fetal car accidents" or something like that on Youtube, which is kind of weird. I don't know why I like it but I know it reminds me that I need to be always cautious on the road because there are crazy drivers anywhere. They are super dangerous!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loving biking, either bicycle or motorcycle. I'm kind of mad at myself now as not ever having my own motorcycle even although I had a M1 license 6 years ago. I never got any supports when I said "I'm gonna to buy a bike." I understand it not safe and it seems immature in some sense, but should I just be immature at that age? I would not regret even if I fell off from my own bike if I had one, but I kind of regret I have never had one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gotta fix my bike soon, meh...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--![images]({attach}/images/bike_day.JPG)--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bike_day" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/bike_day.JPG" width="353" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="life"></category><category term="biking"></category><category term="bicycling"></category></entry></feed>