<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PJ the Pooh</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.pjthepooh.com/</id><updated>2016-10-09T20:20:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Japan Trip</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/japan-trip.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-09T20:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T20:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>YM</name></author><id>tag:www.pjthepooh.com,2016-10-09:japan-trip.html</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Recently several of my friends asked me for tips on Japan because they have planed or are going to plan their first Japan trip, like I did half a year ago. My girlfriend outlined our trip previously so I decided to share it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late March of 2016, we went to Japan for the first time. PJ had always wanted to visit Japan, and was even tempted to study the language. We were able to make one of these wishes come true. We stayed in Japan for about 2 weeks, and visited 7 cities. Before the trip we did a lot of research and compiled a detailed plan. This was the first time we have traveled together to a country where neither of us spoke the language. After this unforgettable trip, we decided to share our experience and tips we have collected throughout our trip in this foreign country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="cherry-blossoms"&gt;Cherry Blossoms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, we planned our trip during Spring Break, just in time to see the amazing cherry blossoms bloom in Japan. This iconic flower only blooms for a short period of time, that varies between a 1-2 months period (usually late March to early April) across Japan. If you would like to see the beautiful sight of roads lined with cherry blossoms, be sure to do your homework and check approximately when these pretty flowers will bloom in the area you are visiting. The exact dates varies every year, but the overall pattern is relatively correct. Blooming was later than expected this year, but we got to see the breathtaking sight of cherry blossoms on our last day in Japan, in Ueno Park in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Cherry Blossom" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/cherryblossom.jpg" width="600"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-89" src="http://www.huang2huang.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/CherryBlossom-1-1024x1024.jpg" alt="Cherry Blossom Collage" width="750" height="750" /&gt;--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image below shows the forecast for 2016 (as of April 27, 2016); follow the link in the image header to obtain the updated forecast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jnto.go.jp/sakura/eng/index.php"&gt;Season Cherry Blooming Forecast (Date of First Bloom)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Cherry Blossom Forecast" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/map_cherryblossoms.png" width="400"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="osaka"&gt;Osaka&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was Osaka. A must-see sight in Osaka is the &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Osaka Castle&lt;/span&gt;. At this well-known castle, we were able to learn about the history behind the castle and see a slight glimpse into the historical culture of Japan. The castle is surrounded by a moat and the Osaka Castle Park that is home to many cherry blossom trees. The observation deck inside the castle is a great place to see the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Osaka Castle" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/osaka_castle.jpg" width="750"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Dotonbori&lt;/span&gt; is the place to go for the Times Square-esque light ads. This is where the Glico running man advertisement is. Try to go at night to see the light ads against the dark sky, and walk amongst the crowd of people to either eat lots of great Japanese food or shop around the night market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Dotonbori" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/dotonbori.jpg" width="700"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="kyoto"&gt;Kyoto&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Osaka, we rode the Shinkansen for 0.5 - 1 hour and arrived at Kyoto Station. Walk out of the station, and you will be greeted by the &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Kyoto Tower&lt;/span&gt;. Kyoto Tower is the tallest building in Kyoto. We suggest you view the tower at night, to see the red tower contrast against the night sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Kyoto Tower" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/kyoto_tower.jpg" width="400"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kyoto, being the old capitol of Japan, is filled with shrines and temples. Many tourist would visit Kinkakuji Golden Temple. However, we only had one day in Kyoto and the Golden Temple was too far north. In the end, we decided to go to &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Fushimi Inari-taisha Shrine&lt;/span&gt;. This shrine has pathways lined with thousands of tori gates that loops around the back mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Fushimi Inari Taisha Shrine" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/fushimi_inari_taisha_shrine.jpg" width="500"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="hakone"&gt;Hakone&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next stop in our adventure was Hakone, to see the famous Fuji Mountain. Deviating from our Airbnb living accommodations, we decided to stay at the &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Hotel Green Plaza Hakone&lt;/span&gt;. This hotel has an onsen with an amazing view of Fuji Mountain. The first day we arrived, the fog was too thick for us to see anything. Fortunately, the next morning the fog disappeared, allowing us to see the magnificent view. The view made the hotel price and the transportation hassle (subway -&amp;gt; train -&amp;gt; bus -&amp;gt; gondola) worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Hakone Onsen" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/hakone_onsen.jpg" width="700"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional Japanese onsens are separated by men and women baths, and require all bathers to be nude. There are proper steps to using onsens, and specific rules. Be sure to review onsen etiquette before going to one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="tokyo"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our fourth destination, was the busy city of Tokyo. Tokyo is a anime and manga lover's dream. Strolling around Akihabara, our childhood self was jumping with joy. The streets were lined with shops selling figurines and items from Slam Dunk to Dragonball Z to Sailor Moon, and much much more. Tokyo Station and Shibuya allowed us to see the bustling culture of Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A must-see building in Tokyo is the Tokyo Tower. The observation deck of Tokyo Tower provides you with a 360° view of the city. However, we wanted to see the Tokyo Tower from afar. To do this, we walked to the &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;World Trade Center Observatory&lt;/span&gt;. We LOVED this location and the view we were able to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="World Trade Center" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/world_trade_center_view.jpg" width="700"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day of our 6th year anniversary, we wanted to step away from the business of Tokyo, and took a quick train ride to &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Odaiba&lt;/span&gt;, an artificial island a bridge away from Tokyo. From the Decks Odaiba, we looked back at the busy heart of Tokyo and saw the buildings and the Rainbow Bridge. A short walk down the boardwalk will lead you to Diver City Plaza, home to a giant Gundam figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Diver City Panaorma" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/diver_city_panaorma.jpg" width="750"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Ueno Park&lt;/span&gt; our line of sight was filled with cherry blossoms no matter where we went. We went on a Sunday; the park floors were covered with people picnicking under the trees. The cherry blossoms, the people, the music and decorations made this an remarkable memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Ueno Park Cherry Blossoms" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/ueno_park_cherry_blossoms.jpg" width="600"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Ueno Park Lake" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/ueno_park_lake.jpg" width="600"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="yokohama"&gt;Yokohama&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An hour Shinkansen train ride away from Tokyo, is the quitter city of Yokohama. Along the pier are many interesting sites, such as the Yokohama Brick Warehouse (a warehouse turned into a shopping center), a shopping mall, and ferris wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also visited the &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Cup Noodles Museum&lt;/span&gt; and learned about the history of Japanese cup noodles. Let your imagination and food-lover side run wide, and DIY customize your own cup noodles. We were on a tight schedule and could not wait through the long lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Yokohama Cup Noodles Museum" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/yokohama_cup_noodles_museum.jpeg" width="750"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="atami-izu"&gt;Atami - Izu&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last stretch of our trip was Atami and Izu Pennizula. During this last stretch, we stepped away from the bustling city life and reconnected with more nature locations. Right outside of the Atami Station is a feet hotspring, open to the public. At Atami, we ate some cheap but amazingly fresh sushi and sashimi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Atami Feet Footspring" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/atami_feet_footspring.jpg" width="600"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Atami, we hopped on a train for 1 hour and arrived in Ito. At Ito, we walked along the &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Jogasaki Coast&lt;/span&gt;, feeling the strong winds and hearing the loud waves. Down the coast is the Kadowaki Bridge, where our childish side took over and we started running down the bridge while the winds blew at our faces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Ito Coast" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/ito_coast.jpg" width="700"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After walking along the coast, we rode a local bus to the &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Izu Granpal Park&lt;/span&gt;. Luckily, there was a lightshow at the park, and we had time to spare. There were lights everywhere, including multiple light models of dolphins :) The light tunnel slide was so much fun, and got us hyped up for watching the rest of the lights. Each section of the park had a different theme and had captivating lightshows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="Izu Granpal Park Lights" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/izu_granpal_park_lights.jpg" width="700"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, this was an extraordinary trip. The sights, the food, the culture, the childhood memories, allowed us to understand this interesting country. With this trip under our belt, we are able to take on more adventure, and tackle more countries where we do not know the language. Until the next journey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you find something useful here.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="japan"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="tokyo"></category></entry><entry><title>Fall Off the Bike</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/fall-off-the-bike.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-17T20:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T20:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>PJ</name></author><id>tag:www.pjthepooh.com,2016-09-17:fall-off-the-bike.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is a bad day. I fell off my bike (bicycle, not motorcycle), and it was my first time falling off. As I did not have any protection, except my helmet of course, and it was in a pretty damn fast speed, so my legs and knees were bruised. Most sadly, my bike crashed on the ground and the handler was deformed. Yup, I bought a new bike a month ago and was about to ride it to work on a daily basis. This morning I was trying to get familiar with the route from home to the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Market St. There was a bus stoping in front of me blocking half of the road. I wanted to accelerate and pass it on the left (yes right? You know you won't stop if you are on a two-wheeled machine). How the hell I could not know there are muni tracks on the middle of Market St (yes right? I must have been living in the city for too long to notice it). I should have noticed it, or I should have never passed buses like that, at least not on Market St. When I saw that track, it was already too late. I fell off at about 10 feet away from the bus's front wheel. Fortunately, the bus had not moved yet. It was pretty dangerous when I look back it now. For those who know me enough, they know I often watch video clips like "top 100 car crashes", "Fetal car accidents" or something like that on Youtube, which is kind of weird. I don't know why I like it but I know it reminds me that I need to be always cautious on the road because there are crazy drivers anywhere. They are super dangerous!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loving biking, either bicycle or motorcycle. I'm kind of mad at myself now as not ever having my own motorcycle even although I had a M1 license 6 years ago. I never got any supports when I said "I'm gonna to buy a bike." I understand it not safe and it seems immature in some sense, but should I just be immature at that age? I would not regret even if I fell off from my own bike if I had one, but I kind of regret I have never had one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gotta fix my bike soon, meh...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--![images]({attach}/images/bike_day.JPG)--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bike_day" src="http://www.pjthepooh.com/bike_day.JPG" width="353" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="life"></category><category term="biking"></category><category term="bicycling"></category></entry><entry><title>Welcome to My New Blog</title><link href="http://www.pjthepooh.com/welcome-to-my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-13T20:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-13T20:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>PJ</name></author><id>tag:www.pjthepooh.com,2016-09-13:welcome-to-my-new-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to my new blog!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="time-flies"&gt;Time flies.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I wrote blog was when I was in middle school, which is n yeas ago, n &amp;gt; 10, when Weibo, Facebook, Twitter did not even exist, but QQ was super popular in China at that time (not quite sure what the outside world was going on). Most young people wrote status or whatever personal stuff on QQ zone, an online social platform similar to Weibo, Facebook today (hmm, actually not quite, but you can imagine it). I did not write it there; instead I found a more quiet place to express my thoughts, a diary website. I was blogging pretty consistently because I felt writing a diary or blog really calmed me down. More importantly, it reminds me my old stories even after years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-would-i"&gt;Why would I&lt;/h2&gt;</summary><category term="life"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>